Or.
I'll share my screen.
I will be just this documentdocumentURI.
Fine, sorry, just give me one moment.
All right, so we.
We started some discussion that we can
just pick it up from...
From the chat,
I'll do a brief summary of this document,.
So basically it is...
Yeah, I'd like some clarity on.
Be often.
like the pros and cons that are listed in
here that I don't really understand.
Yeah, of course, so...
So the first one is the very original one
that we discussed like a year ago, having.
and it won't work. Like A, in my opinion,
well, I mean, I'll say it's my opinion,
but like,
there's no way to make this work at an MQ.
Like,
if we put it below the envoys in the MQTT
session, I mean, we're now,
it's not even resembling MQTT anymore if
we're like chunking,
unless we want to make sure that this is
done across.
everything always. And then even then,
there's a whole bunch of edge cases it
creates with regards to acts and memory
consumption, et cetera,
that I don't even think A should be
considered.
Unless we're interested in radically
changing the relationship of components
It.
that we're dealing with. And
are acceptable to take a bunch of
breaking changes that would probably be
necessary.
That said.
Yeah,
that's probably where we left a year ago.
I say that said, like,
I think this layering in some ways could
I...
make sense of having this at, you know,
in the protocol crate,
but something that is just a wrapper
around MQT that both telemetry and RPC
can share,
because there's no reason for it not to
be shared code.
Yeah, potentially, yeah.
I don't necessarily dispute that.
Hopefully.
Right, yeah.
Yeah, no,. No,.
It's here just for the completeness of
the picture.
Yeah,. So the second option is to...
Build on top of streaming,
which has its own pros and cons.
One of the pros that is, I understand,
not.
Uh.
On the table right now is that we kill
two birds with one stone,
so streaming and chunking.
So it turns out streaming does not have,
frankly any request for that.
So no need...
Well,
doesn't that one case still apply for
streaming?
The one with the multiple records,
like asset discovery,
report 10 to 20 discovered assets in one
operation?
Wouldn't that be a conventional stream?
That would be,.
I mean, if there is, if there is a,.
So basically if there is no other way
around it,
but otherwise you can just have,
you can just assemble every all this
pieces together on the response side and
send it through the checking,.
So there is like.
Well, not quite right, because, like,
there's a there's a there's a one-to-one
For that.
Yeah,
I understand that that every piece makes
relationship between serialization and
deserialization types.
its own sense. Yeah,.
That's all that we we we talked about it
before. Yes, that's all understandable,
but it's like it seems like it's not hard
requirement.
It's just okay that would make.
Yeah, I don't dispute that.
I just want to be very clear that I don't
think that's a chunking scenario.
It's not pure chunking scenario,
but it's not pure streaming requirement.,
So it's like nobody says, oh,
we want in this way and not the other way
around. So I understand that.
Well, I know,
I don't think chunking is the right
approach.
If that problem is a problem we want to
Agreed, because...
solve, like,
I don't think we're hand waving, oh,
we could do it. No,
I don't think you do it with chunking.
Like,
I think that brings the serialization.
Yeah,
because I think you want to receive them
one at a time.
Exactly,
and you want to deserialize each
individual like entry uniquely, right?
And that's not the chunking scenario.
That is the opposite of the chunking
scenario.
What if we just want to send an array of
objects?.
It's more that the timing of when those
assets become discoverable.
But it's the...
Is the interesting part here.
So as I understand that scenario,
asset A might be discoverable at time
stamp zero,
asset B might be discoverable at time
stamp.
0.
1 seconds and we want to send the asset
that becomes discoverable immediately,
but we also want to keep the stream alive
because we think the next asset is coming
soon.
Okay, well then...
Yeah, and to be clear,
I'm not saying we have to like, you know,
ignore this scenario or this scenario
should mean that we implement streaming
to do chunking.
I'm not saying any of that.
What I'm saying is that that scenario I
don't think is chunking and is something
else.
And if that scenario is like high
Yu.
priority, then we have to consider that.
And if it's not,
I'm happy to just ignore that scenario.
Okay, yeah, I.
Yeah, let's keep that scenario in mind,
but just to add some context,
I don't think we should consider that a
high priority scenario.
I think the other file,
the true chunking one that we have had,
I think they definitely are the more
higher priority.
We should optimize for that.
Let's not optimize for this one scenario.
Okay.
But just to for myself,
just to clarify if that would be a
sending array of objects,
would that be a considered good chunking
use case?.
Well, see, the thing is, like,
it's the array,
it's the many things that makes it
appropriate for, as Tim pointed out,
discovered a different time.
You have an ongoing communication that is
sending things with arbitrary things in
between, blah, blah, blah.
Yeah, that's case is clear.
That makes it the stream.
But any single one of those,
you might want to chunk also,
depending on the size, right?
And that's why I think chunking and
streaming are kind of...
different from like,
like chunking is like the idea that it's
related to the content and knowing that
you need to deserialize several payloads
together, right?
That's as opposed to like, you know,
what's going over the wire.
No, yeah, I understand.
My question is in General: do we not do
we consider it is a bad use of chunking
if we just want to sense array of objects?
.
Yeah,
because you don't have control over
Yes, there's no chunking.
whether you're chunking or not. Like,
I mean, if you set,
if your payload is an array,
it may get chunked, but like,
I don't think there's actually any.
like correlation between the two other
than just maybe your payloads longer
And it.
because it's an array.
And then again,
an array is not the scenario that Tim's
describing, right?
Like an array is known at one time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, no argue with that.
No argue with that.
The team scenario is pure streaming,
like all clear.
So, if you wrote,
if you wrote the deserializer and
Is just like.
serializer for the array of stuff,
like we don't have any first class
support for deserializing arrays, right?
Like the way invoker and executor work is
there is a some T that is like an invoker
for T and an executor for T,
or actually it's a TREC and a TRESP,
right?
And the point is that the TREC and the
TRESP payloads have to be.
You know,
you have the serialization built in,
and it's like a one-to-one for this
invoker only serializes this type of
thing, right? So, yeah,
like the array of stuff,
like there's no concept of an array in
there. It's like a data type.
You're getting executor,
you're executing requests that have a
specific format.
If that format is going to be an array,
I mean, like,
I guess if you have some bespoke array
class, like my array something, like,
I guess you could make it.
If you wrote the serializer and
deserializer for it, sure.
But I would say that that's, like,
I guess, but that's not even, like, again,
to me,
chunking would just kick in automatically
if the size gets too big, right?
Yeah,
like it wouldn't get chunked on the array
boundary.
Rather than failing because it's over max
size.
Yeah.
Instead,
chunking would just auto start chunking
it up and splitting it up and assembling
on the other side, in my opinion.
All.
OK, let's move on.
Said.
So the third option is...
Special invoice for chunking support.
And I think to answer your questions
about the...
Efficiency and all of that,
it just so I didn't.
I didn't consider that option.
The first option I guess here to modify
existing MRPC API just adding that.
Both for the chunking options of Invoker
and executor.
So that makes perfect sense and all those
commands that you asked about.
Or they are just in comparison between
these three options,
so it doesn't consider that option of
modifying the MRPC.
But like,
can you explain like more about like what
the safety consider like,
like there is like a bunch of stuff in
there that I didn't really understand.
Well, safety is more on the like a memory.
So, like a DDoS kind of stuff, attack,
'cause like for chunking,.
We know the limits,
so we don't receive more than we...
So we know ahead of time if we can handle
this.
The full message or not.
So they're like for streaming.
It might be some ways to overload us.
But again, it's more.
Well, what's the overload risk?
I don't understand.
Well,
we we don't have is it's more like on the
implementation side than in principle,
I guess.
Because the stream is not can be not,
it's not bounded by definition, so.
I mean,
receiving isn't bounded by definition
either, like, like...
Like,
there's an unbounded channel right now on
a receiver in Rust, right? Like,
because it's a like,
there is no way to rate limit quas 0
messages and not, I mean,
we're talking quas one here,
so I guess theoretically you have a max
of 65,535, but I mean,
that's still even if, if that's like...
the limit you're dealing with,
that's still like extremely memory risky
with large payloads.
Like that's just a natural consequence of
receiving a whole bunch of messages and
not like getting rid of them out of
memory.
Yep, got it. Well, let's...
Buts.
I don't put much,. I guess in this.
So I just didn't have much time to kind
of think all of that through.
It's obviously heavily AI-ed.
So when I read it,
so it made some sense to me.
So by I didn't mean.
Specifics. I guess this case.
I don't let me see,
I don't remember all the questions here.
Do you remember...?
Yeah, I mean,
I just wanted to go over that table and
like understand the recommendations.
Here you have like ship soonest,
safest under load and attack,
lowest compatibility risk,
lowest total protocol cost.
I don't know what a protocol cost is.
Is that like bytes on the wire?
Is that engineering cost?
Like I don't know what that is.
Um...
And for the product.
Yeah,
I just don't really understand like the
conclusion that this document gets to.
For the protocol cost,.
It is on the wire, but it's not a big one.
Basically,.
There is one extra message here and there,
it's not like it's a...
It's a big deal.
Hero.
Is that this table dimension by
dimensions?
No, it was the conclusion table.
Oh, including table, OK, the summary one.
Yeah, like, I don't know.
So, the.
Option.
Well,
that's all I've explained before that.
So, what was compatibility risk? Is,.
What was the B?
It's on top of the streaming.
Oh.
So.
Well, for streaming, you have, it's a,
you have, you will have to,.
You will have to have like a complete new
implementation of streaming first,
and then to have that chunking on top of
it,. So it's not.
And now, on its own,.
It's so you don't have this back mobility
And now, on its own,.
It's so you don't have this back mobility
issues regarding that when it is when you
work on transfer to level you have to.
issues regarding that when it is when you
work on transport to level you have to.
Because it's invisible for the.
Current client and servers,
so they will just receive some garbage on
the wire, not on the wire,
but they won't be able to find.
Won't be able to serialize, deserialize,
correctly.
Well, not exactly, because again,
A is would almost certainly necessitate
breaking changes across the entire SDK.
So I don't really think you could argue
that that's going to be more compatible.
Like, yes, it's invisible,
assuming everything is upgraded,
but like the changes like conceptually to
support the idea that the client,
like the lowest level of the SDK is.
aggregating content are,
it would almost certainly have serious
ramifications on message delivery
guarantees, et cetera.
You'd probably have to rewrite
significant parts of the protocol
themselves to accommodate that.
Well, again,
there is still some old clients that.
Can participate in the exchange and they
want to be able to understand the traffic.
Whereas in B&C, if you don't.
It's just a completely separate thing,
right?.
OK, I guess there is, I mean.
Stu.
So it's maybe.
Go through this bigger table,
which gives us a little bit on.
But again, it seems like we all.
Agreed on that the C-like approach,
but just modifying existing RPC.
Let's not argue about things that we
don't even consider anymore.
Okay, so in that case,
I did do some analysis.
I didn't have a ton of time,
like I mentioned last week,
I wasn't going to,
but I did take some time to analyze what
we have right now and some issues that
might come up with trying to do that. Now,
I do think it's doable,
but there are some considerations.
Particularly around.
Well, okay,
we could get into the specific,
I don't want to,
if you want to talk generalities,
we can do that first. But I do have, like,
yeah,
I did look at the implementation and I
think it's doable. If we cut, like,
you have to like look at the wire version
that you get and be able to.
keep a legacy path for 1.0,
you could swap to 2.0. The issue,
the biggest issue I see is that a
chunking framework introduces new classes
of errors, not like a software class,
but like new types of failures that we
hadn't previously considered,
like for incomplete messages.
et cetera,
which is a little difficult with the
existing error definitions that we have.
And mea culpa here,
we kind of screwed up something in the
rust error definitions that changing them,
adding new types is a breaking change for
us. Again, we should have caught that,
but.
We didn't, it's not,
the kinds are not non-exhaustive, Valerie.
For AIO protocol error,
this was something I'd been trying,
like the error definitions in Rust I'd
been trying to fix before connectors
became a high priority and then the work
got deprioritized and I never got to it.
Again, that is.
something I would have liked to have
gotten to, but we didn't.
And now we would have to eat that now,
but that's a Rust specific issue and I
don't think the other languages need to
tie themselves into knots to deal with
like an engineering failure that we had.
And if we're putting the wire protocol
version, then...
I mean,
if we have a breaking change with that,
it's probably OK.
Yeah, but it's like an API one,
but that's like Rust specific.
Yeah, true.
Issues that we'd have to solve would be
that it is a little dicey to do the 1.
0 versus 2.0 pivot,
because by the time you find out what the
protocol version is,
you read the first packet off the wire,
and then in a chunking scenario,
you'd have to read more.
Which means you had to receive it.
Now that's a surmountable problem,
and the problem is
that the code probably gets a little ugly
because you have to pass some ability to
read into like some delegation after
reading one packet here and then,
or not pack, yeah,
you read one MQTT packet here and then
you have to like read more packets over
there and then some, it's a little weird,
but like, eh, whatever, you can,
you can deal with it. But like, yeah,
it's a little tricky.
engineering wise and code cleanliness
wise, but it's doable.
I think the question we would have to
consider here that would look at a real
implementation of how that would work is,
is the wire going to end for chunking?
Are we going to be aware of the size of
the packets when we sent them out? This
has implications on how we divide up the
chunks, right? Are we lazily doing it, i.
e. trying to send a message,
if it fails for being too big,
cut it in half, try to, if it fails,
cut them in half again.
That seems like the most efficient way to
do it.
But maybe there's a way to do it better
if you knew things ahead of time based on
the type that was defined for the invoker
and executor.
Maybe there's something we could do there
to make it easier.
This also assumes that the max packet
size is not going to change.
And furthermore,
the amount of properties that are on
something can,
that's included in the max packet size.
So we're thinking about payloads here,
but we need to leave overhead for user
properties, et cetera,
which are completely dynamic.
Like we can't stop the user from setting
1000 user properties on this thing, right?
So it has to be like somewhat dynamic.
Tim, you look skeptical of that statement.
I'm thinking on the API side,
users going to pass down what they think
is 1 giant message,
including one set of user properties.
We would know at that point at least how
big the message would be.
Oh yeah, that's a good point. Yeah, yeah,
that's a good point. That's a good point.
And I was going to say we also should be
getting Max packet size from the MQTT
Okay.
broker on Connect.
So I don't think we need to shoot a
message just to see if it gets accepted
or not,
No, no, no, I don't mean shoot them at.
Like what I mean is that knowing that
especially since these are big messages.
like it's on IoT Hub,
we tried to do this to calculate the
packet size ahead of time.
And I'm not saying it can't be done,
but it's a little complex to do to
estimate the packet.
Like I remember Oliva,
you and I tried to do this on Python and
it never worked properly. So.
This was like an IoT hub problem though,
not an MQTT broker problem.
Yes. Yep.
I think we've talked with like the IoT
hub service folks and they say that they
don't even understand how Max message
size is calculated at this point.
Sure.
What I meant is that we tried to estimate
I don't think AIO is necessarily.
the size of an individual message based
on the inputs from the API.
And I think you kind of have to build the
packet to really know, I mean, maybe,
I'm sure there's a way to do it. We just,
I was, yeah, it's a little,
There's some estimation that we have to
have fallback anywhere.
but like I think it's doable.
It's just a little, yeah.
Um, so yeah, if we...
Sure.
And Maxim, you did some uh,
funking PUC last year, right?
I did,
I still have it in the in the branch,
Did we?
but I I honestly didn't check it.
What what? What is there.?
Yeah, maybe worth looking at that as well.
Yeah,. But Speaking of the Max size.
But yeah, if we...
Go ahead.
Like.
I don't remember if we agreed on
something workable was suggested in the
chat this morning, but.
We don't know the other party at the
other end of the...
Yeah.
That's the interesting part,
because if we send something too big,
Yes.
they just don't get it.
Like they can't send us an error back.
They just don't get it.
Yeah, because I understand it's a problem.
Yeah,
because there could be a different
negotiated max size between the two
different clients attached to the broker.
So there needs to be some kind of meta
negotiation and that meta negotiation we
have to assume will be valid across
connections,
which is not true at an MQTG level,
but Arnav seems to say that we can make
that assumption. So
Hopefully.
At Queue maybe.
Okay,. Well,
that's kind of an interesting point,
this idea that we need a handshake
between the two parties before the
chunking can actually get going.
That is something that so far the
streaming protocol is not built for,
an existing RPC protocol is not really
built for either.
That could be the signal that we're
looking for to say that...
Chunking needs to be its own protocol and
its own model.
What?
If we ref the protocol version,
then if you have something that's like
that's 1.0, right?
And we send something with 2.0,
it'll just send the like invalid protocol
version back. So then we know it's at 1.0.
So like adding the handshake in,
I don't think necessarily means that we.
Need a new.
Crotocol.
I'm very hesitant to add more envoys that
have like basically the exact same
Yeah.
surface,
but just have a different implementation.
Yes.
Especially because like when would you
choose the old one now that we have
Yeah, you never would.
You would never choose the old one.
chunking? Like you never would.
It's strictly worse, right? Now,
like obviously that helps us sidestep a
Yeah.
bunch of the breaking change issues that
we would have on Rust in particular,
although maybe not quite because there's
still this whole like generic error.
But that's, again,
that's a Rust specific thing.
Don't worry about that in making
decisions here. That's for,
that's our cross to bear.
But yeah,
like it is easier to make a second envoy,
or maybe not easier in terms of like
effort,
like because like you have to rewrite a
lot of like the same code again,
and then the maintenance becomes trickier
because now you have it in two places and
you could try to do some like don't
repeat yourself stuff and isolate some
stuff out, but at the end of the day.
A lot of like the parallelization stuff
is just going to be kind of nasty no
matter what. And then yeah,
you have two things that have basically
the exact same surface,
but like one's called chunk.
And the whole point of the chunking is
that it's opaque, right? Like,
isn't that I just want to send stuff and
like you figure out how to chunk it up?
Like.
I don't,
when am I going to want to as a customer,
I'm going to, oh yeah,
let me take the chunking one.
Like I don't even want to think about
chunks because I don't, I'm not even,
I'm not using,
like chunking is a concept at MQTT level
because it's the stuff's too big and
they're using our protocol, not MQTT.
The MQTT aspect is opaque.
So I want to just.
send, here's the data, you can take it,
right? Like,
I don't want to think about MQTT max
message size that was negotiated without
my knowledge, by the way, in the sessions,
right? Like,
I don't want to be thinking about MQTT if
I'm using an abstraction on MQTT.
To circle back on one point, here,
this idea that...
Chunking is like strictly better as a
user experience perhaps.
I would say that if we have to have some
sort of handshake message beforehand when
doing chunking,.
That in and of itself makes the protocol
a bit heavier,
which seems unnecessary for smaller RBC.
A one-time cost at like setup.
Like, I mean, okay, yeah.
If you're shooting off lots of RPCs, yeah.
Okay.
So like.
What if it could be in the application
context? What do you think about that,
Valerie?
Could we put something like this in the
application context so it didn't have to
be negotiated multiple times?
Oh, so is this, yeah, I mean,
that would make sense, right?
I, I don't know how viable that is.
I'm just like, it just came to me and uh..
If we're using this for telemetry and RPC,
like, yeah, your packet size is the same.
.
That would make sense to me as far as
just where to store the packet size,
but then, I mean,
if the executor is something different,
then that'll be per indication.
Oh right, because yeah,
it has to be negotiated on an envoy to
envoy basis because the executors could
be on different systems with different,
okay, yeah, yeah, yeah, never mind.
But like,
even like telemetry is just like,
you can't negotiate that. So like,
that's a like,
like I think we should talk about RPC
here,
but once we kind of figure out what we
want for RPC,
telemetry is a little different.
Do we want to?.
In.
Why not if you can have something that's
too big? I mean, I suppose with telemetry,
you don't have the back and forth.
You could argue with the customers,
split up the payload themselves, but like.
..
Again,
then they're just doing raw bytes instead
of like using our built-in serialization.
And the key part is our serialization
Is useful.
comes from that you can use with code Gen.
and the watt and all that kind of stuff,
and you'd be losing all of that if you're
like thing in the code Gen.
like the watt that you use in the code
Gen. is too big, then it all falls apart.
Like the manual case only works if you're
manually doing it.
Yeah,
but then RPC or to Andrew would be a
separate thing, right, if we're doing.
RPC extension, new version,
then for the telemetry would be the same,
just newer.
Yeah, on a wire.
But like the point is that like...
There's no way to respond and say that I
don't accept this protocol version.
Oh, okay, yeah,
that's an interesting point.
Like you're just.
You're just sending it to the right,
like you're assuming the other sentence I
can receive it, which I mean,
in some ways,
it's not you're always doing that,
but that's more true now.
But like codegen still matters, right?
So like, you know,
if we talk about like fixing it in place,
like putting it in the existing RPC
invoker and executor,
codegen just like works with this
out-of-the-box as opposed to having to
rewrite all the codegen stuff to deal
Yeah.
Yeah, should be nice.
with this. Now granted,
it's probably a find and replace if the
API is the same. But again,
why are I don't want to keep this thing
hanging around that we have to,
or then like you said,
if it's an optimization issue, Tim.
then it's like at the cogen layer,
it's got to figure out if it needs
chunking or not needs chunking.
And that's going to be on an application
and even like negotiated connection basis,
right?
Yeah.
Like depending on what the broker
negotiates with you as a client on a MQTT
level is going to affect what your chunk
size can be. So it's like.
Just because it's like in one deployment
this wipe might work.
You deploy the same code somewhere else
and now it doesn't work because now you
need the chunking one.
Like that's where having it like auto
negotiate the chunking is extremely
beneficial in the portability.
There is some argument to saying that,
like, if your sides are mismatched,
this is something that the customer
should be responsible for. Like,
if we're talking, you know, RPC,
where they own the handbook or an
executor, like...
If they know that their executor can't
support chunking,
then they shouldn't be sending things
that are too big, right?
Like that is application domain. And.
What, what, what I'm trying to say,
Valerie,
is what is too big can change per
deployment, like...
True. Well,
like this is a current problem, right?
Like...
something and how's the code Gen.
supposed to know if you need chunking or
not for for like a given like model
that's being used as like the
Over, yeah, yeah,
that's where RBC handles it.
serialization payload type, right?
I have a question.
So the main use cases for us.
Sending was model.
And what was schema registries?
Schema registries.?
Is it possible that we are over
optimizing for these use cases? I mean,
like they're not gonna run on like small
devices. We're talking about optimizing,
removing handshake code, right?.
That's what is that?.
That was one of the points.
But...
Well, I...
Demo registry operations should be
relatively infrequent.
I think that's kind of like when I first
receive a message from a device,.
I don't know.
I'm going to do a lookup on its schema so
I can parse the data.
That should be a one-time thing per
device.
And.
Against my argument or pro my argument.
Hard to.
The Valerie point on...
Out.
How important is it for a user to know
that they are chunking because they are
responsible for both sides?
Or perhaps 1 side.?
I'm definitely leaning towards you.
Should be aware if you are chunking or
not.
I would rather not try to do this for the
user.
What's the benefit of the user knowing?
Like to me, like I'm, I don't,
Yeah.
I have never sent something on a wire and
wanted to know how many packets guy got
split up into unless I was the one
serializing the packets myself. Like,
Mostly for back compatibility at the
moment,.
So if I have a device that wants to do a
get on schema registry and service sends
back a chunked response,.
But maybe that device is old enough that
it doesn't know how to do chunking,
that's a problem.
But that's like if they don't support
chunking, they just can't get it at all,
When we use different topics.
right?
Like the interesting thing about chunking
is that if we...
If we chunk something,
it's because we couldn't have sent it
anyways, right?
Like that's something that the flow
wasn't possible without chunking because
it's too big for one message.
You do.
Like unless we are getting into some
fancy math where we are chunking a little
bit less than what we could,
but honestly that feels like a very close
edge case if we can get close enough to
the right size that we chunk things into.
These messages aren't possible before.
So maybe now we aren't sending an error
saying you tried to send something too
big. That's maybe the only difference,
right?
Because before your message would fail to
send.
But like,
like for the get request example,
like if they do a get request and we try
and send them something back as chunked
and then they can't receive it,
like they weren't going to get it anyways,
right?
Our send was just going to fail before.
True.
Also, if you send a, oh no, I guess, yeah,
T-Rec and T-Rest weren't related,
so you might not chunk on the outgoing,
but you might chunk on a response. Okay.
So we want to use, I mean,
I may say something stupid,
but we want to use the same topic for the,
so we're not going to have like a
separate topic topics for the chunking
flow.
Like request chunking response,
chunking something like that.
See why.
Intuitively,
I would say I don't really see what that
would add other than complexity.
I mean, you have support,
you have a client, and uh,
invoker executor that support both
versions like...
I don't know?.
Yeah,
I can see maybe that actually helps with
We.
the server when like a client's getting
something unsupported from the server.
But like, ultimately, we already,
like if the server, I don't know. Yeah,
maybe with the server compatibility,
I just.
Yeah, to be concrete,.
That would give us the ability on the
executor side to try to publish to the
chunking topic,
get a no matching subscribers,
and then the executor knows I can't send
chunking,
but we still hit the same issue that...
Well, no,
the executor knows if if the executor
But yeah,
like what do you do with that information?
gets a request that's at 1.0,
they know not to send trunking back.
Yeah, nothing changes.
Oh, that's true. Yeah,
because the request would have the wire
The.
protocol version.
Yeah, the request is for the problem,
right?
That you send chunks as the request.
Yeah,
that's what that that's why we made a
wire protocol version.
Yeah.
And then, and then I mean,
then you can say,
if you're trying to send a chunk response
back in there at 1.0, you can say, like,
you just sent an error back instead,
saying the response is too big,
Too big.
we couldn't send it.
I don't think we need separate topics. No,
that's fair.
Oh.
So the burden solved.
Alves sure.
I think it does,
unless there's something I'm just like
IT.
completely missing. Like it...
I think like the versioning gets messy if
we,
if there's anything else we have a
version for,
because like this is a very simple
version, right?
Like there is a clear like legacy flow
that we can use that really isn't that
complicated for us to have that logic in
code,
Yeah.
because you kind of have to support one
and two, right? But you know,
Yeah.
if we have something else where then it's
like.
Well,
like you can see where that could get
But that, that's a future US problem,
right? Like...
complicated,
but that's kind of Futurist problem of
like versioning already. You're just like,
I never felt super confident we could do
This is...
it.
This is one of those that I think we
could.
This, I this is reminding me,
I think Carl was spearheading this idea
of feature flags rather than protocol
versions way back when,
Yeah.
Yeah, he was, he was, he, he, he,
he argued valiantly for that.
Exactly, that,
and I think that did come up from
for this exact Raul, yeah.
chunking.
Yeah, I.
And I lost that battle.
You did. You lost. You did. You did.
Don't remember why, but yeah.
But that is something interesting here,
right? Because it is,
chunking is not about the version,
it is whether both sets support chunking.
We're using the the version to.
But I mean, at this point,
I think we can correlate those two things
within this context.
And maybe in the future,
C.
that's not for like some future feature,
maybe not,
but that's future us problem to deal with.
Okay,.
So let me see if I'm up to speed on
what's going on.
So we're suggesting chunking be added
kind of invisibly to existing RPC clients,
or sorry, RPC envoys.
The protocol version for RPC gets a bump
up to 2.0. Since this is a, I think.
Additive breaking change or however we
define that back when and we're saying.
Discard streaming for now.
Nobody's really asking for that.,
Varun said.
The one scenario that actually sounds
like streaming is not as much of A hard
requirement for us right now.
So we can kind of just shelve that.
Yeah, and I like,
I think you could implement RPC over
streaming as well,
but if Varun doesn't want the effort to
build a new wire protocol, then like,
yeah,
let's not do that because that's like a
whole extra thing.
And then we can cross that when they need
on voice for like the individual stream
Yeah.
entries or frames or whatever they're
called, right?
Like that are like individually
serialized.
that's a completely separate API surface
that would need to look different.
So again, caveats for Rust,
I don't know that we can actually make
this change in our SDK without a breaking
change for Rust, but again, that is.
Our problem, not.NET's problem, so...
What are we going to do? Yeah,
like the error cases are probably,
there's going to be some new errors that
we will have to eat and or like figure
out how to assign to existing errors that
like may reduce the informational value.
And the other thing would be,
what did I write here?
Um...
There was something else,
but I'm not remembering what it is.
I also would still flag that I am a
little skeptical of the ability of us
through a whatever client library
surfaces that we have available to us in
protocol to be able to estimate a packet
size. That's because,
especially in Rust where the packet that
goes on the wire is actually
Yeah, we're going...
backed by a bespoke buffer that isn't
exposed through the API.
Like Valerie knows what I'm talking about.
Like packet estimation in Rust is going
Interesting.
to be dicey. Maybe you can do it in.
NET easier.
I think we will have to do some amount of
leaving a little wiggle room,
and that's probably just going to be what
it is.
Yep, that's fine,. That's fine.
I think we're going to be doing the same
thing in.NET as well.
The.
Other considerations here, are we,
so yeah, I guess we'll know, oh, queuing,
like offline queuing is also a thing.
Like, suppose you're not connected, right?
How do we know what can go on the wire
when the max packet size hasn't been
negotiated yet? That's kind of a problem.
Oof.
Do we have to maybe do we have to get the
first one to send successfully before we
Overnight.
start shooting them off?
I don't think it's like send success.
Like I think we would preemptively want
Well, also, we're not actually...
to do it,
but we don't know what the like max
packet size is until we connect,
but we do want to be able to queue
offline messages.
But that also means that we can't
Yeah.
actually queue anything that.
This is where, like,
I think we can best effort decide trunk
size, and then, like, like you're saying,
like I don't think we can calculate it
for sure,
so that first message we maybe have to do
some of that trial and error of resizing
the trunks.
And.
So annoying.
Great question. Yeah,
if we kill the session, that would not.
Surely,. Surely they do that?
The other part there is that I don't
think in reconnection scenarios we would
expect the Max packet size to change on
the second connect.
What about before the first connection
though,
which is the way that you have to do it
in Rust.
Yeah.
Mhm.
We set up the envoys before the
connection.
Yeah.
But you don't publish on that on or you
don't have to publish on that envoy
before connecting.
Oh, actually, I suppose you... Yeah,
you always do the subscribe first.
No,
and you'll always do your subscribe burst.
So actually,
I think maybe we're in the clear.
Maybe.
Except for for telemetry, but again,
let's put telemetry in a box for now.
Yeah, well,
that's future us problem telemetry.
Yu.
Yeah,
I think it would block on the subscribe.
So it would just queue up the sub and
then yeah, no public. Yeah,
Yeah, it'd be OK.
I think it's fine. It's probably fine.
Let's double check that though, Valerie.
As long as we have that be able to pass
in dynamically somehow, yeah, that'll be.
Again, that's a problem for us to bear,
not everybody else.
That's doable.
And if we can set this up in some way
that like that value can change to the
invoker.
Okay, fundamental question,
since we're kind of in this area, anyways,
do we want to allow the user to influence
these chunk sizes in any way?.
Like if a user for some reason wants
really small chunked messages because the
receiving end is a low processing unit.
Device perhaps.
I don't like the idea of the user like
choosing whether to chunk,
Gut feeling? No.
but I do like the idea of I know
something about the other side that the
SDK can't.
And this comes to another kind of big
question I have too, which is like.
Okay,
if the invoker sends something and the
executor doesn't support chunking,
they can send back the error.
If the executor is a smaller max packet
size, the invoker sends something too big,
they just don't get it. Like,
how do we handle that? There's like,
that's a timeout. We don't.
I'm also uncomfortable with options that
get like weirdly aligned. So it's like,
Too big?.
I don't know how we can recover.
okay, what, like as a user,
what takes precedence between my chunk
max chunk size and my max broker packet
size that I've configured, right?
they choose like too big.
Like what if one's bigger than the other?
Like, it's like,
what if I set my chunk size bigger than
what the broker negotiate?
Like it's a little.
Especially because we're not exposing
certain things that the broker responds
with. I mean, actually,
are we maybe we are exposing the connect
now? No,
we're not exposing the connect on session,
I don't know.
are we, Valerie? I don't think so.
So again,
that's like maybe a design choice that we
made,
but there like the point of the AIO
session client was to like, you know,
streamline things. So.
Yeah.
My opinion is I,
unless there's like a real need,
I'm always hesitant to give the user
options because then it's like, oh,
what about this one? How does this,
like it increases the complexity of the
I understood, I understood.
I, yeah.
matrix of where things can go wrong.
I'd probably rather add it later.
Like I think there is a valid use case
where you don't want to set your max
packet size small just because your
executor has a small max packet size. But.
..
Until someone runs into this problem,
like,
let's just make sure that we have our
options struck as like, you know,
extendable, like non-exhaustive,
so that we can add stuff to in the future.
We use builders, whatever,
and then I'd rather just add it later if
we need to.
Okay, I think that's reasonable.
OK,
so chunking will happen automatically if
we detect message is too large.
We decide the message size.
We've got a new protocol for doing this
on both Invoker and executor side.
What else are we forgetting here?.
And we're taking it on faith that the
broker is not going to change its max
packet size.
That's an assumption that we are making
that is not guaranteed by the protocol,
but we are guaranteeing based upon our
understanding of MQ's functionality per
Arnav saying that it won't change it on
us.
But like that's an assumption that we're
baking in to make this work.
That is not true at the protocol layer.
I liked your idea of putting something
around this on the application context,
where potentially if there is a reconnect,
the value in the application context
could change,
and this is just something that we read
every time.
I mean,
it would have to be available through the
manage, like again, this is getting,
I guess this part,
the application context is general,
but like in Rust,
because the session doesn't have an
application context,
only the protocol envoys do,
so like one of them would have to take
There is some weird linking, right?
responsibility of like updating it and
then like what's the race condition there
and then like.
You know,
you have to get it off the managed client
Well, the race condition is our fallback,
how we have to resize the packets anyways,
in Rust.
if we calculate wrong, right?
Like that fallback's always there.
Yeah.
It's just not efficient, right?
So, but yeah,
we can take on faith that the packet size
isn't going to change on us.
So that answers that question that I had.
That we're going to do our best effort at
approximating when calculating the chunks,
but like we probably have to leave some
headroom just in case.
And is the wire going?
protocol going to indicate a set number
of packets.
i.e.
will we have calculated all of the chunks
OLD.
ahead of time?
And will the properties be on every
message?
That works if the size can't change.
I think when the user supplies our API,
this really large message,
we should be able to know how many chunks
it will be sent in,
and I do think that's valuable
information to have on the receiving side.
I need it.
Yeah, I think that it's, yeah,
probably better to have it than not have
it.
I think we could probably get by without
it, but if we could have it,
why not have it?
One other interesting thing here is the
caching side of things for RPC.
So currently in Vanilla RPC we have both
dedupe caching,
Yeah.
which is not super hard for us to
integrate here, and also replay caching,
which we get into that same discussion
about, you know,.
What happens when the replay cache just
grows and grows and grows and grows
because they're sending some 1GB message
or something.?
Don't do it!
But and also like.
Yeah.
Like I can't control your memory usage
for you. I'm a library.
Because I assume you would want to like...
I just do what you tell me to do.
Like I assume you would want to act after
you received everything because we're not
saving to disk and we're not giving you
the pieces as you go, right?
Like I think we reassemble and then give
it to the SDK.
Yeah.
Yes, we cannot act anything. Yeah, well,
Like what if we run out of packets?
Life.
Yeah, that is a thing. Yeah,
I would want a higher packet ID.
That's.
Pretty.
Like I would want more than 10.
Let's put it that way.
I might like a packet ID greater than 10.
I'm not saying we need 65,535 of them,
but...
But maybe that's something too that if
you would the like executor know their
max packet ID if they get something that
says it's chunk one of 65,
000 then we can reject the message.
Yeah,
so the executor right now in Rust can't
But.
get that,
but there's no reason we couldn't pipe it
to the executor once again through the
managed client.
Like that's something that comes on a
CONAC,
but the executor won't know it right away
up until the connection happens.
but also like the invoker can't reject.
This is also a little weird in it right
now, the envoys are connection agnostic.
So this idea that they're supposed to be
like pulling data from the CONAC.
to like inform their behavior is a little
bit clashing with the design of not just
this protocol envoy,
but like any hypothetical envoy.
The point is that the whole reason that
they were designed the way that they were
is to be connection agnostic and just
have an injected connection that manages
itself.
So now here we're talking about needing
to get stuff.
off of like the information about the
connection, which is,
does create like a certain timing issue.
Does, you know, I mean,
we've been flirting around this problem
for a long time. You know,
it was kind of inevitable it would
eventually come up because, you know,
it turns out being completely connection
agnostic is a little.
A little tricky.
Okay, getting back to the replay cache,
in particular though,
are we suggesting that?
We're just going to try to emulate
existing RPC behavior and store as much
of the.
Invoker or sorry,
store as much of the response as we can
in memory for the.
China,
it's been so long that I've looked at
this cache;. How does that work exactly?.
Hey, good news,
Raul just joined us and he's the cash man.
I think if we care about each piece.
Oh.
If we care about every piece,
I don't see how there's any option other
Ohh, hello.
than caching this though. Like,
we're just going to get rid of guarantees
that thread's going to want.
Now, I will say, devil's advocate here,
as much as I've been advocating for
sharing the envoy and that I think this
should just be magic and it should just
work and everything else is silly.
Perhaps the argument for a dedicated
chunking envoy is that it has less
caching behavior. Like that.
is a real argument for what Maxim had
initially proposed,
that if we want to have reduced caching
support for this type of RPC,
that's there.
Although I don't know how like.
It could just be a flag...
Is lack of caching acceptable? I mean,
I guess what does the cache mean to we
resend every single trunk? Like,
there's no other option.
Yeah, and as soon as we, yeah,
as soon as we reduce like caching,
all of our delivery guarantees are like
kind of messed up. So like, yeah,
how much utility does this thing even
have without caching?
Like maybe it doesn't, like, you know.
But it is weird to get every single chunk
again if you missed one or something.
Yeah, and of course, you know,
we will get...
Yeah,.
There's not a good reason to do anything,
but like, you know,
if someone blows up their application by
like eating all their memory because they
made silly choices in their lives,
it will become our problem. Now, again,
that's not a reason to make bad choices.
In fact,
that that has been happening to me
recently in that like, you know,
Oh, I'm not,
I'm receiving infinite quad 0 messages
and I didn't drain the receiver and now
my application crashed.
Why did that happen? No,
because you didn't,
like you let infinite quad 0 messages
build up. Like,
what do you think was going to happen?
But like, you know,
it will become our problem and we just
have to be able to be like, no.
It's not actually our problem.
It's your problem. Don't like, you know,
send 2 gigabytes worth of data at a time
and then expect it to be cached when you
have like a 400 MB memory limit.
Like don't do that maybe.
So Carter, to your initial point here,
where you were talking about do we need
That could idea will be our problem.
like a special envoy.?
To signal that we want or don't want
specific caching behavior,
I think that's something we could just
add as like a flag in vanilla RPC.
And this is something that might even be
of value to vanilla RPC users,
like if they don't care about this replay
cache,
they don't want memory being taken up on
their device because they don't expect to
ever need to replay.
That would be more of a side benefit,
but I don't think we need a separate
envoy specifically for cache management.
Negotiation.
Yeah, I agree as well.
I think we should probably either, yeah,
do what you said with the flag or just do
best effort and then, you know,
maybe don't send large data if you don't
have large memory. But yeah,
like I'm just playing devil's advocate.
I do, I do still agree with you there,
Tim.
Got no, so it's all good, all good.
Okay.
Dedupe. Cache,.
Let's give this a minute or two of
thought., So I'm guessing if we.
I do not know how this works.
So I'm guessing if we want to do.
This chunking protocol thing,
it's going to end up looking a bit
similar to what you designed in streaming,
where we're going to have this header
that says under score, under score,
chunk and it says chunk index.
And we're going to be able to use those
same like timestamp and index things that
we were talking about.
Just need the index on that.
There's no restart and continue.
La.
Yeah,. Oh, actually yeah,.
That's a good point. We should back up.
Do we care about, like, the...?
Tim Stem is probably enough.
You can't.
Oh, time stamp, sorry,. It's on itself.
Because you wouldn't get the.
Like if you start in the middle of a
trunk from the end broker, like you don't,
you can't deserialize the data.
Yeah, that's a nonstarter.
Yeah.
Yeah, so there's no recovery in that one.
And there's probably, as a result,
a different message delivery, Gary.
Like, yeah, what are you what happened?
I mean,
I guess it's just the same as getting a
corrupted message,
so maybe I'm overthinking it.
Because like receiving part of the data,
like what if you just received half a
Well.
payload?
Like it's not going to deserialize, right?
Like that's the same category of error.
It's just surfacing it, or I mean,
It's also.
it could surface the same way,
but it's a different cause.
It's also something you want to kill
sooner rather than later.
If someone's sending like a really
massive payload and the first message is
dropped for whatever reason,
you would want to tell the invoker shut
Yeah, you should just...
up, stop sending me stuff.
Yeah, drop all the next ones.
And would you act them though or should
Yeah.
they be re-delivered?
Because the thing is,
You like them.?
the broker is supposed to deliver them
all and then
But the broker actually won't re-deliver
until you disconnect.
Application layer decides that they
aren't needed.
You wouldn't want them redelivered.
In this scenario,
where we're picking up mid chunks.
Just in the first.
Oh yeah,
I think the most realistic one is like
one of the messages has expired.
So it's not really the first one.
Let's say it's the last one,
like they queued up in a broker for some
reason and then like they come and by the
time, or I mean, no, I guess yeah,
the first one is the most likely to have
expired. So one of them expired,
that's never coming. So then yeah,
I'm inclined to think you just did.
discard the whole thing.
But that does maybe lead to more data
loss. Because yeah,
basically it's if one message expires,
the whole thing expired.
I think that's a reasonable.
Yeah.
It feels worse intuitively,
but like I don't think it actually is
That's a reasonable requirement.
worse because yeah, if one expired,
then they're all expired. So.
Yeah,
this is not streaming where we can drop
Exactly.
Right.
frames, yeah.
OK, then we don't,.
We cannot communicate back right, so...
This is vanilla RPC,
so we do have a response topic that we
can send error messages to.
We would need to define a new error type
But not the end over.
saying something like chunk was not
initial chunk or missing chunk,
something like that.
So Invoker would know to stop sending
chunks.
But if it's if the chunks are on the
response, you can't do the same thing.
And.
Unless we introduce a response topic or
something.
Good.
What do you mean by that exactly? Valerie?
, You're saying?
Well, if the executor is sending, yeah,
like if the executor is sending a chunk
If we're chunking in the response as well?
.
response, which totally valid scenario,
right? Get request on schema.
Then if the invoker missed the first
trunk, trunk 2, whatever,
there's no way for the invoker to say,
don't send the next 100 trunks.
Like there's no way to respond currently.
And we could add a response topic if we
Oh, that's true.
wanted to,
if this is something that we need to be
able to like cancel from the invoker side.
I don't think that's necessarily the end
of the world.
We do get to unsubscribe from the
response topic on the invoker side.
But we don't do that. Like,
we subscribe to that for the lifetime of
the invoker and regular RPC,
because there's no reason to keep
Do I understand right that?.
subscribing, unsubscribing,
or in Rust at least.
You talking about the case when...?
Java is still coming from the invoker,
and will be to the to the.
Let me ask you.
So it's simple scenario that drives home,.
So Invoker sends 1 non-chunked message,.
It makes it to the executor just fine.
Executive wants to send some chunked
response, one of those messages gets lost.
How do we signal to the executor to?.
Shut up, something you didn't.
You might be right,.
Maybe we do stay subscribed for the
lifetime of the clients.
But even if you unsubscribe,
that doesn't tell the executor to stop
sending.
Exactly,
it only that's a subscription with the
broker.
There's no meta communication with the
other side of the envoy relationship.
Well,
I'm suggesting that was the meta
communication saying I the invoker am no
longer subscribed. I no longer want those.
That's what a subscription is.
You could say maybe there's like a
connectivity loss scenario around that.
That assumes that you get no matching
Subscribers,
which you also can't really assume.
What else would a no-matching subscribers
mean in that context?.
No,
so you might not get the no matching
subscribers, right? Like,
this is kind of a, yeah, like,
Ohh, sorry, I misheard you.
I'm pretty sure that's just kind of like
a informational can be sent.
I don't know that it's fully required,
and I mean, like we've discussed before,
it's not actually treated as an error in
Rust.
Or not.
Yeah, and I don't does.
net even support the concept of like no
Turn.
matching subscribers because like a lot
of clients like don't.
It does.
Okay.
Yeah, no,
we would receive that if the broker sent
it, but that's fair. OK,
so that's not a great mechanism for
communicating back.
I mean,
the downside of just sending a bunch of
messages that can't...
Be handled like.
It's not great, it's not,
there's no error happening there, right?
Like that is not causing message loss,
it is causing just more data than
necessary.
Yeah,
the invoker would assumably resend the
requests and try to receive the response
response chunks again.
The replay cache, yeah.
Okay, yeah,.
I don't think it's worth trying to invent
some communication from the invoker to
the executor specifically for this one
error case. Especially this is MQ,.
We don't deal too much with like packets
being lost generally.
I think that's.
I mean, of course, one should be pretty.
Yeah, it's.
It's at least once delivery period.
I think that's worth maybe calling out in
the doc as an assumption,
or not as an assumption,
but as a possible failure case that this
does not cover,
but that that's rare enough that we don't
care.
Yeah,
like the most likely the most likely way
for a loss is an expiration,
and I don't actually know off the top
what the broker's like expiration
behavior is anymore, so I don't.
An expiration that they would want to be
taking into account, anyway.
Yeah, and yeah,
I also don't think we should couple too
hard to expected expiration behavior of
the broker,
because that's like a little dicey,
especially something that could change on
The.
us.
Speaking of expiry,
if we've got a couple of minutes still,
the message expiry per MQTT message we
send is kind of interesting in a chunking
scenario now.
Um.
The simplest approach might be to say
that we still treat message expiry the
same way Vanilla RPC does.
But then how does that affect things on
the you do cache?
Send a countdown, like had a countdown.
Yeah, that is that how?.
Or.
Maybe similar like we were going to do
for the streaming that current.
Down down timer for the call.
So that was like a header level timeout
that we sent.
I'm thinking about the message expiry
interval which is sent per message.
The message expire interval is going to
be similar to that in streaming,
where it kind of like we would.
Valerie,
we have issues with the volume in the
Decrease it.
room, so if you can a little bit speak up.
Sorry,
I think with streaming that was like we
were doing something similar where the
message expiry in the header we are also
going to documentdocumentURI.
that you would end up with something
twice as long towards the end of the
stream.
Yeah, for your sake, Maxim,.
I think at this point,
try to mimic what vanilla RPC does with
message expiry interval, I guess,
and you'll have to let us know where that
falls apart.
That'll be kind of interesting on the
caching side,
because if we're talking about delivering
gigabytes of data...
Yeah,. But then user can disable caching,
OK.
So for your context on the vanilla RPC
flow, we use the message expiry interval.
Both as a way to kind of set the timeout
for broker to deliver the message,
but also as a timeout for.
Some caching stuff on the execute side.
And that's kind of the interesting bit
here I think for you.
We are well overtime,
but is there anything else you guys
wanted to talk about that we could help
Maxim with here before we break?
Ohh.
Not maybe as the most urgent topic,
but I think running out of packet IDs is
something we need to consider because we
could just very easily as the SDK by not
Yeah.
hacking brick things and the customer
can't do anything about it.
Like that's fully in our ownership and...
Yeah.
That's like that we can't we can't break
up MQTT messages for that.
And...
So whether we have some limitations on
how many chunks can be sent in something,
or if we send partials to the user or
something for them to say,
you need to store this if you're worried
about it,
but there's something that needs to be
handled there.
because that is not an issue we want to
find in production.
No.
This is assuming we want delayed acts
just like Vanilla RPC,
where we're doing something like.
Not.
I mean, yes,
but I don't know that you even consider
We have to, right?
it delayed acts in some way because like,
yeah,
For the caching, yes.
like we wouldn't want to act it until we
give it to the user, right?
Like if we're pull,
if we're aggregating everything and we've
aggregated 50 messages and then we crash,
then like the user couldn't have saved
those to disk, right? So like.
Exactly.
If we act them, they won't come again.
And that's just data loss.
I see.
Yeah.
And yeah, so that mean, and the,
I'll have to check the MQDD spec again.
I don't recall this off the top,
but I also think that the max packet ID
is negotiated with the broker as well,
which means that we don't know that till
Yes.
a connection happens,
which is really annoying.
Yeah,
that one's going to be a weird twist.
Yeah, basically, yeah,
I think chunking is going to require
awareness of the details of the
connection and assume that those details
will not change across connections within
the same session.
OK.
I think that's reasonable, yeah.
OK.
It's going to be annoying for us on Rust,
but yeah, we'll figure something out,
I guess.
Isn't everything annoying on rest?
That's kind of the point of the language,
Yeah.
I mean, it means we handle things, but...
right?.
Sure, sure, sure. We trust you guys. Okay,
. So next steps. Here,. Maxim,.
I think the first thing we need to do is
reach out to Varun and Arnav and, say,?
Hey,. We're pivoting here a little bit.
We don't want to do streaming because
that apparently isn't what anyone needs.
Really. We're going to try to.
To do chunking for the user as part of
our existing RPC protocol.
And we'll give him a chance to respond on
that. If he flails his arm and says,
what are you guys doing?
We need streaming as well,.
Then we can sync back up on that.
No,
I think he Arnav and Varun was on that
conversation from this morning,.
So it is pretty much Varun Green Light,.
I think he understood the suggest
approach right.
I'd probably still get an explicit like.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I mean, like, yeah,.
He's he's aware of the direction, So,.
But yeah, absolutely, and...
Okay, yeah,. Just give him that. Heads up,
give him a chance to say yay or nay,.
And then at that point, I think.
We're going to need a new design Doc to.
Noodle over. OK, OK.
We're so sorry by the way, this is...
Yeah.
Well, no.
Not how it's supposed to happen, but.
It's...
Good that we were able to discuss and
then come to a conclusion sooner than
later, right? So all good.
Yeah, OK, alright.
Well, thank you, everybody.
And I apologize,.
I'm not as well prepared for this one.
It's just been very short, sort of,
from the Friday. And time's good.
This is good, Don.
Yeah, no worries.
Definitely lacking some knowledge of the
internals of the existing SDK, so if.
Definitely lacking some knowledge of the
internals of the existing SDK, so if.
Yeah, I would probably familiar, like,
if we're talking about doing this within
the existing invoker and executor,
there's a lot of like...
traps in there and I would definitely
recommend becoming a lot more familiar
with like how they work because there's a
like they're pretty complicated for a
request response mechanism.
There's a lot going on.
Yeah,
now when I have sort of like an area to
focus on, it will be easy for me.
Thank you.
OK, thanks folks.
Alright, thank you everybody.
Thanks.
Well, thanks. Bye.
I want like.
Thanks.
And this meeting, because this, I think,
has been rebooting, yeah,
Yu.
it's been rebooting all the time,
very annoying.
Things that was quite.
Be on camera.
Oh yeah, there's an end meeting.
To like you.